(Master Shenguan is a eminent monk of Nanzhao, and the matter is of great consequence.)
(السيد شينغوان راهب بارز من نانتشاو، والمسألة ذات أهمية بالغة.)
(You Chen'an strongly urged the Three Judicial Offices)
(حثّ يو تشين آن بشدة المكاتب القضائية الثلاثة)
(not to perform an autopsy on the sacred body)
(عدم إجراء تشريح للجثة المقدسة)
(to avoid conflict between the two states.)
(لتجنب الصراع بين الدولتين.)
(As expected, Vice Envoy, Gao Luoqian raised objections,)
(وكما هو متوقع، أبدى نائب المبعوث، غاو لوتشيان، اعتراضات.)
(even stirred up trouble by using the fact)
(بل وأثار المشاكل باستخدام هذه الحقيقة)
(that Chu Chu is a woman serving as a coroner.)
(أن تشو تشو امرأة تعمل كطبيبة شرعية.)
(In court,)
(في المحكمة،)
(I could only avoid the confrontation for the moment)
(لم يكن بوسعي سوى تجنب المواجهة في الوقت الحالي)
(and seek another way.)
(وابحث عن طريقة أخرى.)
(Fortunately, His Highness and I)
(لحسن الحظ، أنا وصاحب السمو)
(thought alike)
(متشابهة في الفكر)
(and had You Chen'an examine the body for me.)
(وطلبت من يو تشين آن أن يفحص الجثة من أجلي.)
(The outcome was favorable,)
(كانت النتيجة إيجابية)
(yet I could not shake the feeling)
(ومع ذلك لم أستطع التخلص من هذا الشعور)
(that His Highness was keeping other concerns from me.)
(أن سموه كان يخفي عني أموراً أخرى.)
♪Embark on a farewell without saying goodbye♪
♪انطلق في رحلة وداع دون أن تقول وداعاً♪
♪Build a bridge between life and death♪
♪ ابنِ جسراً بين الحياة والموت ♪
♪Hear a voiceless declaration♪
♪استمعوا إلى إعلانٍ صامت♪
♪Break disguises, cross illusions♪
♪اكسر الأقنعة، واكشف الأوهام♪
♪A fleeting life and delusions♪
♪حياة عابرة وأوهام♪
♪The surface always conceals♪
♪السطح يخفي دائماً♪
♪Separate cause and effect♪
♪افصل بين السبب والنتيجة♪
♪A twisted path, rising and falling♪
♪مسار ملتوٍ، صعوداً وهبوطاً♪
♪Seek the path amid the hazy unknown♪
♪ابحث عن الطريق وسط المجهول الضبابي♪
♪Writing oblivion with a sharp blade♪
♪كتابة النسيان بشفرة حادة♪
♪No matter how far, I gaze at the light♪
♪مهما بعدت المسافة، أنظر إلى النور♪
♪Fearing no wild lands, I press on♪
♪لا أخشى الأراضي الوعرة، أواصل المسير♪
♪To see the tides of the world once more♪
♪لرؤية أمواج العالم مرة أخرى♪
♪The deeper truth is buried, it grows♪
♪الحقيقة الأعمق مدفونة، لكنها تنمو♪
♪Until it is set free♪
♪حتى يتم تحريرها♪
=The Imperial Coroner S2= (Adapted from Idle Girl's The Constable's Wife)
=المحقق الإمبراطوري الموسم الثاني= (مقتبس من رواية زوجة الشرطي لـ Idle Girl)
(This story is entirely fictional.)
(هذه القصة خيالية تماماً.)
=Episode 8= (Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org)
=الحلقة 8= (ادعموا المشرفين، شاهدوا الحلقة على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org)
(Music Office)
(مكتب الموسيقى)
His Majesty favors rising newcomers,
يفضل جلالته الوافدين الجدد الصاعدين،
with the Jing Family backing them in secret.
بدعم من عائلة جينغ سراً.
Half the court now stands behind Commandery Prince An.
نصف أعضاء البلاط يقفون الآن خلف الأمير آن قائداً.
How could he not grow arrogant?
كيف لا يصبح متغطرسًا؟
By that measure,
وبناءً على ذلك،
he has been
لقد كان
rather restrained with us.
كانوا متحفظين بعض الشيء معنا.
Nonsense.
هراء.
By using criminal cases to interfere in local appointments,
باستخدام القضايا الجنائية للتدخل في التعيينات المحلية،
Commandery Prince An's intentions
نوايا الأمير آن في قيادة المنطقة
are impossible to miss.
لا يمكن تفويتها.
And that is called restraint?
وهل هذا ما يسمى ضبط النفس؟
Exactly.
بالضبط.
Everyone,
الجميع،
do not be discouraged.
لا تيأس.
On the contrary,
على العكس تماما،
this is the right moment to press the advantage.
هذه هي اللحظة المناسبة لاستغلال الميزة.
This...
هذا...
How so?
كيف ذلك؟
It might
قد يكون ذلك
just turn the tide.
ما عليك سوى تغيير مجرى الأمور.
Jiang,
جيانغ،
what do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
Yes.
نعم.
That day,
في ذلك اليوم،
His Majesty did not reject Commandery Prince An's request,
لم يرفض جلالته طلب الأمير آن قائداً للقيادة.
yet
حتى الآن
he reprimanded the Princess Consort.
وبخ الأميرة القرينة.
You mean
تقصد
we should start with the Commandery Princess Consort An?
ينبغي أن نبدأ بالأميرة القرينة آن؟
But she and the Prince
لكنها والأمير
are deeply devoted,
إنهم متفانون للغاية،
always acting in unison.
دائماً ما يتصرفون بتناغم.
That...
الذي - التي...
So devoted, indeed.
يا له من إخلاص!
Precisely because of that,
ولهذا السبب تحديداً،
bring one down,
أسقط واحداً،
and the other
والآخر
will be dragged under as well.
سوف يتم جرها إلى الأسفل أيضاً.
A fine move.
خطوة موفقة.
Jiang,
جيانغ،
you have a plan?
هل لديك خطة؟
Come,
يأتي،
drink.
شرب.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
The matter of Xie Huaiding
مسألة شي هوايدينغ
has made progress.
لقد أحرز تقدماً.
Speak.
يتكلم.
Years ago, Xie Huaiding had a child
قبل سنوات، أنجب شي هوايدينغ طفلاً
with a singing girl.
مع فتاة تغني.
According to our informants,
بحسب مصادرنا،
(Menghua. Guard of Nanzhao's Eldest Prince) the child has now ended up in Nanzhao.
(Menghua. حارس الأمير الأكبر في Nanzhao) انتهى الأمر بالطفل الآن في Nanzhao.
Heaven favors Nanzhao.
السماء تُفضّل نانتشاو.
So the Three Judicial Offices of Great Tang
إذن، المكاتب القضائية الثلاثة في عهد أسرة تانغ العظيمة
are nothing but empty names.
ليست سوى أسماء جوفاء.
Such vital intelligence, yet they knew nothing.
معلومات بالغة الأهمية، ومع ذلك لم يكونوا يعلمون شيئاً.
It seems Xiao Jinyu
يبدو شياو جينيو
is not as meticulous as claimed.
ليس دقيقاً كما يُزعم.
How is the Peacock operation progressing?
كيف تسير عملية بيكوك؟
Peacock has taken over all informants
استحوذ بيكوك على جميع المخبرين
around Commandery Prince An.
حول قيادة الأمير آن.
His Majesty's plan
خطة جلالته
is fully in motion.
إنها في حالة حركة كاملة.
We need only wait for results.
كل ما علينا فعله هو انتظار النتائج.
(Map of the Great Tang Realm)
(خريطة مملكة تانغ العظمى)
At present,
في الوقت الحالي،
the Uyghurs and Tanguts in the north,
الأويغور والتانغوت في الشمال،
and Tubo in the west,
وتوبو في الغرب،
all eye the Great Tang with hostility.
ينظر الجميع إلى أسرة تانغ العظيمة بعداء.
Nanzhao sees this clearly
نانتشاو يرى هذا بوضوح
(Xie Huaiding, Cavalry General)
(شي هوايدينغ، قائد سلاح الفرسان)
and seeks to profit from the chaos
ويسعى إلى التربح من الفوضى
to claim its share.
للمطالبة بنصيبها.
I do not wish my people to suffer war,
لا أرغب في أن يعاني شعبي من ويلات الحرب.
yet he takes my restraint for fear.
لكنه يظن أن ضبط النفس الذي أبديته نابع من الخوف.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Let me go.
دعني أذهب.
These years in the capital,
هذه السنوات في العاصمة،
I have grown idle to the bone.
لقد أصبحت كسولاً حتى النخاع.
Those Nanzhao people
أهل نانتشاو
dare think of riding over us,
يجرؤون على التفكير في دهسنا،
I...
أنا...
The frost-forged halberd in my hand
الفأس المصنوع من الصقيع في يدي
will not permit it.
لن يسمح بذلك.
Unless Nanzhao's hostile intent is put to rest,
ما لم يتم وضع حد لنوايا نانتشاو العدائية،
I
أنا
will not return to court.
لن يعود إلى المحكمة.
These seasonings
هذه التوابل
I brought from my home in Qianzhou.
أحضرتها من منزلي في تشيانتشو.
In the Great Tang,
في عهد أسرة تانغ العظيمة،
it's all peppercorns and evodia.
كلها حبوب فلفل وإيفوديا.
You can't find real Qianzhou heat here.
لا يمكنك أن تجد حرارة تشيانتشو الحقيقية هنا.
Let me fan you.
دعني أهوي عليك.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
It's getting late.
لقد تأخر الوقت.
He.
هو.
I need to buy green plums for autopsies.
أحتاج لشراء برقوق أخضر لإجراء عمليات التشريح.
Otherwise I'll miss the West Market.
وإلا سأفتقد السوق الغربي.
I'll head off then.
سأذهب إذن.
Chu.
أن.
I'll go with you.
سأذهب معك.
They're heavy. I'll carry them.
إنها ثقيلة. سأحملها.
He, stay seated.
هو، ابقَ جالساً.
I'll go with her.
سأذهب معها.
You eat.
أنت تأكل.
You go?
اذهب أنت؟
Alright, take it.
حسناً، خذها.
I'm off, He.
أنا ذاهب يا هو.
Take care.
يعتني.
Mm.
مم.
Have a look around.
ألقِ نظرة حولك.
I'll help you.
سأساعدك.
Thanks.
شكرًا.
Deputy Prefect Leng.
نائب رئيس الطلاب لينغ.
Come.
يأتي.
Quick.
سريع.
(Leng Baichuan) Rare to see
(Leng Baichuan) نادرًا ما يمكن رؤيته
(Deputy Prefect of the Capital) you patrolling in person.
(نائب محافظ العاصمة) تقوم بدورياتك بنفسك.
Indeed, Prefect.
بالتأكيد يا رئيس الجامعة.
The streets haven't been peaceful lately.
لم تكن الشوارع هادئة في الآونة الأخيرة.
So I had to come myself.
لذا كان عليّ أن آتي بنفسي.
More than just unrest.
أكثر من مجرد اضطرابات.
It's been quite a scene.
لقد كان مشهداً مثيراً للغاية.
Newlyweds being all affectionate,
كان العروسان الجديدان مليئين بالمودة،
and then that...
ثم ذلك...
Isn't that the Commandery Princess Consort An?
أليست تلك هي قيادة الأميرة القرينة آن؟
And beside her...
وبجانبها...
Second Prince of Nanzhao.
الأمير الثاني لمدينة نانتشاو.
Second Prince of Nanzhao?
الأمير الثاني لنانتشاو؟
Those two...
هذان الاثنان...
How could that be?
كيف يمكن أن يكون ذلك؟
(Three Judicial Offices)
(ثلاثة مكاتب قضائية)
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Chu Chu.
تشو تشو.
Reporting to Your Highness,
تقديم التقارير إلى صاحب السمو،
this is the autopsy sheet
هذه ورقة تشريح الجثة
jointly signed by You Chen'an and me.
تم التوقيع المشترك من قبل يو تشين آن وأنا.
One copy will be kept by the Nanzhao delegation.
سيحتفظ وفد نانتشاو بنسخة واحدة.
The other
الآخر
is for your review.
هذا للمراجعة.
Chu Chu...
تشو تشو...
You Chen'an said
قال يو تشينآن
he will do his best to persuade Gao Luoqian
سيبذل قصارى جهده لإقناع غاو لوتشيان
to honor Master Shenguan's memory
تكريماً لذكرى المعلم شينغوان
and let the matter rest.
ولنترك الأمر عند هذا الحد.
I'll take my leave.
سأغادر الآن.
Chu...
أن...
Jing Yi.
جينغ يي.
You're here.
أنت هنا.
These past few days,
خلال الأيام القليلة الماضية،
I've been holding the scalpel too much.
لقد كنت أمسك المشرط كثيراً.
My hand's gone a bit numb.
لقد خدرت يدي قليلاً.
Seen enough?
هل شاهدت ما يكفي؟
Not yet.
ليس بعد.
Of course not.
بالطبع لا.
Even the ever-unshakable Commandery Prince An
حتى قائد القيادة الذي لا يتزعزع أبدًا، الأمير آن
can be unsettled by matters of the heart.
قد تتأثر استقراراتهم بأمور القلب.
What do you mean, "matters of the heart"?
ماذا تقصد بـ "شؤون القلب"؟
Chu Chu and I...
أنا وتشو تشو...
Watch your words.
انتبه لكلامك.
If such jokes get out
إذا انتشرت مثل هذه النكات
and stir trouble,
وإثارة المشاكل،
I'll tell Leng Yue everything
سأخبر لينغ يو بكل شيء
about your hidden savings.
حول مدخراتك الخفية.
The autopsy record is done.
تم إعداد سجل التشريح.
It matches the statements
يتطابق مع التصريحات
from Jing Yuan and the others.
من جينغ يوان والآخرين.
We've checked every household where rituals were performed.
لقد فحصنا كل منزل تم فيه أداء الطقوس.
No issues found.
لم يتم العثور على أي مشاكل.
The case is closed.
تم إغلاق القضية.
Since You Chen'an has endorsed the autopsy report,
بما أن يو تشينآن قد أيد تقرير التشريح،
we can silence Nanzhao's objections.
يمكننا إسكات اعتراضات نانتشاو.
Still, Your Highness,
مع ذلك، يا صاحب السمو،
you seem uneasy.
تبدو متوتراً.
From Gao Luoqian's stance
من وجهة نظر غاو لوتشيان
when he demanded the body,
عندما طالب بالجثة،
he appeared overly confident.
بدا واثقاً بنفسه أكثر من اللازم.
Shenguan's death
وفاة شينغوان
gave Nanzhao
أعطى نانزهاو
a ready pretext to challenge the Great Tang.
ذريعة جاهزة لتحدي سلالة تانغ العظيمة.
And Jing Yuan,
وجينغ يوان،
who was deeply devoted to his master,
الذي كان شديد الإخلاص لسيده،
also said
وقال أيضاً
there were no hidden ailments.
لم تكن هناك أمراض خفية.
Just as we were closing in on Peacock,
وبينما كنا نقترب من بيكوك،
the master died suddenly.
توفي المعلم فجأة.
Taken together,
مجتمعة،
it's too much of a coincidence.
إنها مصادفة مبالغ فيها.
Besides, we still have a key witness
إلى جانب ذلك، لا يزال لدينا شاهد رئيسي
to verify.
للتحقق.
You mean Qinxiang?
هل تقصد تشينشيانغ؟
Master Shenguan was revered by the people
كان السيد شينغوان يحظى باحترام كبير من قبل الناس
in both lands,
في كلا البلدين،
and respected by his peers and disciples.
وكان يحظى باحترام أقرانه وتلاميذه.
He was not a frivolous man.
لم يكن رجلاً تافهاً.
He went to the Music Office in plain clothes
ذهب إلى مكتب الموسيقى بملابس عادية
not for romantic entanglements.
ليس للعلاقات الرومانسية.
Until the truth is clear,
إلى أن تتضح الحقيقة،
this case stays open.
تبقى هذه القضية مفتوحة.
Go back to the Music Office
ارجع إلى مكتب الموسيقى
and take a hard look at Qinxiang.
وألقِ نظرة فاحصة على تشينشيانغ.
As for the Music Office,
أما بالنسبة لمكتب الموسيقى،
I'll bring Yue.
سأحضر يو.
Between husband and wife,
بين الزوج والزوجة،
it's about trust and standing together.
الأمر يتعلق بالثقة والتكاتف.
No matter how big the issue,
بغض النظر عن حجم المشكلة،
it must be laid out plainly.
يجب توضيح ذلك بشكل واضح.
If we hide things from each other,
إذا أخفينا الأشياء عن بعضنا البعض،
we might as well part ways.
ربما من الأفضل أن نفترق.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
You're clear-headed about everything,
أنت تتمتع بعقلية صافية تجاه كل شيء،
so why do you get stuck when it comes to Chu Chu?
فلماذا تواجه صعوبة عندما يتعلق الأمر بتشو تشو؟
Snap out of it.
استفق من غفلتك.
Yue keeps saying you must've done
تستمر يو في قول أنك لا بد أنك فعلت
something to wrong Chu Chu.
هناك خطأ ما في تشو تشو.
I can only put up with this for one night.
لا أستطيع تحمل هذا إلا لليلة واحدة.
She really said that?
هل قالت ذلك حقاً؟
Put your mind at ease.
اطمئن.
You've been too focused on Chu Chu lately,
لقد كنتَ مُركّزاً جداً على تشو تشو مؤخراً،
and not on me.
وليس عليّ.
As if I haven't cared enough.
وكأنني لم أهتم بما فيه الكفاية.
I dropped everything on my plate
أسقطت كل شيء على طبقي
just to work this case with you.
فقط لأعمل معك على هذه القضية.
Of course my innocence
بالطبع براءتي
has to be watched over by my lady.
يجب أن تراقبه سيدتي.
Enough.
كافٍ.
May I ask which Sir
هل لي أن أسأل أي سيد؟
and Madam...
وسيدتي...
It's you again.
أنت مرة أخرى.
This time,
هذه المرة،
are you here to hear a tune,
هل أنت هنا لتستمع إلى لحن؟
or to ask questions?
أو لطرح الأسئلة؟
I've already told you
لقد أخبرتك بالفعل
everything I should.
كل ما ينبغي عليّ فعله.
So you still insist
إذن ما زلت تصر
you had nothing to do with Master Shenguan?
لم يكن لك أي علاقة بالمعلم شينغوان؟
I don't even know
لا أعرف حتى
what kind of master he was.
يا له من سيد!
If you want answers,
إذا كنت تريد إجابات،
you should've asked him.
كان عليك أن تسأله.
That's a shame.
هذا مؤسف.
Master Shenguan is dead.
مات المعلم شينغوان.
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
He's dead?
هل مات؟
That's impossible.
هذا مستحيل.
You barely knew him,
بالكاد كنت تعرفه،
why care so much?
لماذا نهتم كثيراً؟
After all,
في النهاية،
we did cross paths once.
لقد التقينا مرة واحدة.
My apologies to you both.
أعتذر لكما.
If there's nothing else,
إذا لم يكن هناك شيء آخر،
I need to get back to work.
أحتاج للعودة إلى العمل.
Qinxiang.
تشينشيانغ.
Mr. Zhao is here again.
السيد تشاو هنا مرة أخرى.
The two of you...
أنتما الاثنان...
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
please excuse yourself.
أرجو المعذرة.
My dear.
عزيزي.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Leaving already?
هل ستغادر بالفعل؟
Take care.
يعتني.
Qinxiang.
تشينشيانغ.
Hurry up.
أسرع.
Mr. Zhao is waiting.
السيد تشاو ينتظر.
Move it.
حركه.
(Music Office)
(مكتب الموسيقى)
Something's off.
هناك شيء خاطئ.
You felt it too, right?
لقد شعرت بذلك أيضاً، أليس كذلك؟
Her reaction to Master Shenguan's death
كان رد فعلها على وفاة المعلم شينغوان
was not that of someone who barely knew him.
لم يكن ذلك تصرف شخص بالكاد يعرفه.
Agreed.
متفق.
When the dancer came out just now,
عندما خرجت الراقصة للتو،
she said Mr. Zhao was looking for her.
قالت إن السيد تشاو كان يبحث عنها.
Mr. Zhao?
السيد تشاو؟
- Zhao…
- تشاو...
I'll take a look.
سألقي نظرة.
My lady.
سيدتي.
Don't alert them.
لا تنبههم.
Let's play the eavesdroppers instead.
لنلعب دور المتنصتين بدلاً من ذلك.
Since Mr. Zhao is here,
بما أن السيد تشاو موجود هنا،
we might as well hear the tune that made her famous.
فلنستمع إذن إلى اللحن الذي جعلها مشهورة.
Sounds good.
ًيبدو جيدا.
(Zhao Senyao, the son of Vice Minister Zhao of Ministry of Rites)
(تشاو سينياو، نجل نائب وزير المراسم تشاو)
Young Master.
السيد الشاب.
Zhao Senyao.
تشاو سينياو.
So it really is him.
إذن هو فعلاً هو.
Qinxiang seems terrified of him.
يبدو أن تشينشيانغ مرعوب منه.
Young Master.
السيد الشاب.
You wretch!
يا لك من بائس!
You dared scheme against me.
تجرأت على التآمر ضدي.
Please spare me, Young Master.
أرجوك ارحمني يا سيدي الشاب.
Young Master.
السيد الشاب.
I was wrong.
كنت مخطئاً.
Please spare me.
أرجوكم ارحموني.
So you even found a monk to shield you.
بل إنك وجدت راهباً ليحميك.
Wasn't he treating your skin condition?
ألم يكن يعالج حالتك الجلدية؟
Treating you?
هل يعالجك؟
You don't deserve to live.
أنت لا تستحق أن تعيش.
You wretch.
يا لك من بائس.
I'll strangle you!
سأخنقك!
Who are you calling a wretch?
من الذي تصفه بالبائس؟
Say it. Who is the wretch?
قلها. من هو هذا الوغد؟
It hurts.
إنه مؤلم.
Senyao.
الصمت.
It's been a long time.
لقد مر وقت طويل.
Beating an official courtesan without cause?
ضرب عاهرة رسمية دون سبب؟
You've grown bold.
لقد أصبحت أكثر جرأة.
Impressive...
بديع...
So you found Vice Minister Jing to back you up.
إذن، وجدت نائب الوزير جينغ ليدعمك.
A misunderstanding.
سوء فهم.
Young Master was only fooling around with me.
كان السيد الشاب يمزح معي فقط.
Just playing.
مجرد مزاح.
Playing?
هل تلعب؟
He was trying to kill you.
كان يحاول قتلك.
Qinxiang.
تشينشيانغ.
Don't be afraid.
لا تخف.
As long as you tell the truth,
طالما أنك تقول الحقيقة،
the Three Judicial Offices will see justice done.
ستعمل السلطات القضائية الثلاث على تحقيق العدالة.
So what about the Three Judicial Offices?
وماذا عن المكاتب القضائية الثلاثة؟
You think you're untouchable?
أتظن نفسك فوق القانون؟
You can just hit people at will?
هل يمكنك ضرب الناس كيفما تشاء؟
Was I hitting a person?
هل كنت أضرب شخصًا؟
Vice Minister Jing.
نائب الوزير جينغ.
Bringing your wife to the Music Office?
هل ستصطحب زوجتك إلى مكتب الموسيقى؟
Your Three Judicial Offices sure know how to amuse themselves.
مكاتبكم القضائية الثلاثة تعرف كيف تسلي نفسها.
Look closely.
انظر جيداً.
I paid for this entertainment.
لقد دفعت ثمن هذا الترفيه.
She agreed to it.
وافقت على ذلك.
Didn't you?
أليس كذلك؟
Yes.
نعم.
Thank you for the reward, Young Master.
شكراً لك على المكافأة، أيها السيد الشاب.
Bad luck.
سوء الحظ.
Say that again!
قل ذلك مرة أخرى!
Ridiculous.
سخيف.
Come, Qinxiang.
تعال، تشينشيانغ.
Get up.
استيقظ.
Let me see.
دعني أرى.
Was it Zhao Senyao who did this?
هل كان تشاو سينياو هو من فعل هذا؟
Thank you, Vice Minister Jing and Madam, for stepping in.
شكراً جزيلاً لنائب الوزير جينغ وسيدتي على تدخلكم.
If you wish to hear a tune,
إذا كنت ترغب في سماع لحن،
I will attend to you.
سأهتم بك.
If not,
وإلا،
I must return to fix my makeup
يجب أن أعود لأصلح مكياجي
and receive the next patron.
واستقبال الزبون التالي.
It's not the first time Zhao Senyao has beaten you, is it?
ليست هذه المرة الأولى التي يهزمك فيها تشاو سينياو، أليس كذلك؟
Master Shenguan was treating your illness.
كان المعلم شينغوان يعالج مرضك.
Do you know he died at the Zhao Residence?
هل تعلم أنه توفي في منزل عائلة تشاو؟
The night you met him,
في الليلة التي قابلته فيها،
did he say anything important to you?
هل قال لك شيئاً مهماً؟
Sir.
سيد.
Vice Minister Huang has arrived.
وصل نائب الوزير هوانغ.
Lord Huang.
اللورد هوانغ.
Lord Gao insisted I come here.
أصرّ اللورد غاو على مجيئي إلى هنا.
For what purpose?
لأي غرض؟
Lord Huang.
اللورد هوانغ.
This is
هذا هو
a selection of the finest Nanzhao spices,
مجموعة مختارة من أجود أنواع توابل نانتشاو،
prepared especially for you.
تم إعداده خصيصاً لك.
I wonder
انا اتعجب
if they suit your taste.
إذا كانت تناسب ذوقك.
That won't be necessary.
لن يكون ذلك ضرورياً.
Officials of the Ministry of Rites have always upheld integrity.
لطالما تمسك مسؤولو وزارة المراسم بالنزاهة.
If Vice Envoy Gao has something to say, speak plainly.
إذا كان لدى نائب المبعوث غاو ما يقوله، فليتحدث بوضوح.
if it is within my ability,
إذا كان ذلك في حدود قدرتي،
I will do my utmost.
سأبذل قصارى جهدي.
Very well.
جيد جدا.
Lord Huang,
اللورد هوانغ،
the court has now concluded
وقد خلصت المحكمة الآن إلى
that our Nanzhao eminent monk died by accident.
أن راهبنا البارز من نانتشاو قد توفي في حادث.
Yet his remains are still kept by the Three Judicial Offices,
ومع ذلك، لا تزال رفاته محفوظة لدى المكاتب القضائية الثلاثة.
which harms Nanzhao's dignity.
مما يضر بكرامة نانتشاو.
So
لذا
we wish to ask you
نود أن نسألك
to have the remains returned.
إعادة الرفات.
That falls under the authority of the Three Judicial Offices.
يندرج ذلك ضمن سلطة السلطات القضائية الثلاث.
Commandery Prince An holds great power.
يتمتع الأمير آن بسلطة كبيرة في قيادة المنطقة.
I fear I cannot be of help.
أخشى أنني لا أستطيع تقديم المساعدة.
Vice Minister Huang, you truly stand upright,
نائب الوزير هوانغ، أنت حقاً مثال يُحتذى به.
not even sparing a glance at Nanzhao's gift.
ولم يلتفت حتى إلى هدية نانتشاو.
We all serve our respective courts.
كلنا نخدم محاكمنا المختصة.
So I hope you will not put me in a difficult position
لذا آمل ألا تضعني في موقف صعب
and grant us some convenience.
وامنحنا بعض الراحة.
If Vice Minister Huang
إذا كان نائب الوزير هوانغ
were rumored to have certain unspeakable tastes,
ترددت شائعات بأن لديهم أذواقاً لا توصف،
and such rumors reached His Majesty,
ووصلت هذه الشائعات إلى جلالته،
it would be enough
سيكون ذلك كافياً
to ruin your official future,
لتدمير مستقبلك الرسمي،
or even cost you your life.
أو حتى قد يكلفك حياتك.
Vice Minister Huang.
نائب الوزير هوانغ.
Are you satisfied with this offering?
هل أنت راضٍ عن هذا العرض؟
As for the affairs of the Three Judicial Offices,
أما فيما يتعلق بشؤون المناصب القضائية الثلاثة،
I will do my utmost.
سأبذل قصارى جهدي.
Still,
ما زال،
I cannot guarantee any outcome.
لا أستطيع ضمان أي نتيجة.
Lord Huang,
اللورد هوانغ،
in the days ahead,
في الأيام المقبلة،
do come by more often,
أزوركم أكثر من ذلك،
so we may enjoy these fragrances together.
حتى نتمكن من الاستمتاع بهذه العطور معًا.
Very well.
جيد جدا.
Zhao Senyao was beating Qinxiang mercilessly.
كان Zhao Senyao يضرب Qinxiang بلا رحمة.
He has always been indulgent,
لطالما كان متساهلاً،
but never openly violent.
لكنها لم تكن عنيفة بشكل علني أبداً.
Yet today he was savage,
لكنه كان اليوم متوحشاً،
as if he harbored a deadly hatred toward her.
كما لو أنه يكنّ لها كراهية قاتلة.
Qinxiang has long endured his abuse,
لقد تحملت تشينشيانغ إساءته لفترة طويلة،
and Master Shenguan then happened to die suddenly at the Zhao Residence.
ثم توفي السيد شينغوان فجأة في مقر إقامة عائلة تشاو.
Follow this lead
اتبع هذا الدليل
and continue the investigation.
ومواصلة التحقيق.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
what concerns me is that
ما يقلقني هو أن
if the truth leads to nothing in the end,
إذا لم تُفضِ الحقيقة إلى شيء في النهاية،
and there is no hidden scheme behind Master Shenguan's death,
ولا توجد مؤامرة خفية وراء وفاة السيد شينغوان،
then
ثم
you will be the first to come under attack.
ستكون أنت أول من يتعرض للهجوم.
Factional strife
الصراع الفصائلي
has always plagued officialdom.
لطالما شكلت هذه المشكلة معضلة في الأوساط الرسمية.
But the Three Judicial Offices act
لكن قانون المكاتب القضائية الثلاثة
only to safeguard the Great Tang.
فقط لحماية سلالة تانغ العظيمة.
Being condemned by many
إدانة من قبل الكثيرين
matters little
لا يهم كثيراً
if the realm remains at peace.
إذا بقي العالم في سلام.
Very well.
جيد جدا.
Then we proceed.
ثم نتابع.
The Three Judicial Offices do not rest on you alone.
لا تقع مسؤولية المناصب القضائية الثلاثة على عاتقك وحدك.
The heavens will not collapse.
لن تنهار السماوات.
Speak.
يتكلم.
What do you plan to do next?
ما هي خطتك التالية؟
Now that there are signs something was concealed,
والآن بعد ظهور دلائل على إخفاء شيء ما،
we must be thorough.
يجب أن نكون دقيقين.
You mean...
تقصد...
The last autopsy was not done by Chu Chu,
لم يقم تشو تشو بإجراء آخر عملية تشريح للجثة .
but by You Chen'an in her stead.
ولكن بواسطة يو تشينآن بدلاً منها.
I will find a way to persuade Jing Yuan
سأجد طريقة لإقناع جينغ يوان
to allow another examination of Master Shenguan's body.
للسماح بإجراء فحص آخر لجثة السيد شينغوان.
This time,
هذه المرة،
Chu Chu will conduct it herself.
ستتولى تشو تشو إجراء ذلك بنفسها.
So you have finally let go of that fixation,
إذن، لقد تخلصت أخيراً من ذلك الهوس،
and will no longer keep Chu Chu out of it.
ولن يمنع تشو تشو من المشاركة في ذلك بعد الآن.
Chu Chu was right.
كانت تشو تشو على حق.
Like any other coroner,
مثل أي طبيب شرعي آخر،
she is a member of the Three Judicial Offices.
هي عضوة في الهيئات القضائية الثلاث.
Since that is the case,
وبما أن الأمر كذلك،
I should
ينبغي علي
choose personnel based solely on
اختيار الموظفين بناءً على معيار واحد فقط
what best serves the case.
ما يخدم القضية على أفضل وجه.
As for their safety,
أما بالنسبة لسلامتهم،
that responsibility falls to me.
تقع هذه المسؤولية عليّ.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Someone from the Ministry of Rites is here,
يوجد هنا شخص من وزارة الطقوس الدينية.
requesting to take Master Shenguan's body.
طلب أخذ جثة السيد شينغوان.
Where is His Highness?
أين صاحب السمو؟
His Highness just left
غادر سموه للتو
for the palace.
للقصر.
Vice Minister Jing went with him.
رافقه نائب الوزير جينغ.
(Ten-Commandment Hall)
(قاعة الوصايا العشر)
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
I, Vice Minister of Rites, Huang Lv,
أنا، نائب وزير المراسم، هوانغ لو،
pay my respects.
أتقدم بخالص التعازي.
What brings Vice Minister Huang here?
ما الذي أتى بنائب الوزير هوانغ إلى هنا؟
I have heard that the Three Judicial Offices
سمعت أن المكاتب القضائية الثلاثة
and Nanzhao have jointly signed off
وقد وقّع كل من نانزهاو ونانزهاو على الاتفاقية بشكل مشترك
on the autopsy findings.
بناءً على نتائج التشريح.
I hope Your Highness will consider the difficulties faced by the Ministry of Rites
أرجو من سموكم أن يأخذوا بعين الاعتبار الصعوبات التي تواجهها وزارة المراسم
and hand Master Shenguan's body over to me.
وأسلمني جثة السيد شينغوان .
Vice Minister Huang, have you informed His Highness of this?
نائب الوزير هوانغ، هل أبلغت صاحب السمو بهذا الأمر؟
I am here by imperial command.
أنا هنا بأمر إمبراطوري.
Then do you have His Majesty's written order?
هل لديك إذن أمر كتابي من جلالته؟
Though Your Highness serves with the Three Judicial Offices,
على الرغم من أن سموكم يعمل في المناصب القضائية الثلاثة،
at the end of the day,
في نهاية المطاف،
you are still a woman of the inner quarters.
ما زلتِ امرأة من الطبقة الراقية.
Many matters of officialdom
العديد من مسائل العمل الرسمي
cannot be made clear
لا يمكن توضيح ذلك
in just a few words to Your Highness.
بكلمات قليلة موجهة إلى صاحب السمو.
So there is no written order.
لذا لا يوجد أمر مكتوب.
Vice Minister Huang, you're in such a hurry
نائب الوزير هوانغ، أنت في عجلة من أمرك
to take Master Shenguan's body.
لأخذ جثة السيد شينغوان.
Is it because the Nanzhao delegation is pressing,
هل يعود ذلك إلى ضغط وفد نانتشاو؟
and you fear His Majesty's inquiry?
وهل تخشى تحقيق جلالته؟
Since Your Highness sees things so clearly,
بما أن سموكم يرى الأمور بوضوح تام،
please do not make things difficult for the Ministry of Rites.
من فضلك لا تجعل الأمور صعبة على وزارة الطقوس الدينية.
If the matter is so urgent,
إذا كانت المسألة عاجلة للغاية،
why did Vice Minister Huang wait until dusk to come?
لماذا انتظر نائب الوزير هوانغ حتى حلول الغسق ليأتي؟
The Ministry has many affairs to attend to.
لدى الوزارة العديد من الأمور التي يتعين عليها الاهتمام بها.
I only just found the time.
لم أجد الوقت إلا الآن.
What a coincidence.
يا لها من مصادفة!
You happened to miss His Highness.
لقد فاتك لقاء صاحب السمو.
With His Highness absent,
في غياب صاحب السمو،
the body may not be moved without authorization.
لا يجوز نقل الجثة بدون إذن.
If you are truly anxious,
إذا كنت تشعر بالقلق حقاً،
you may enter the palace now and see His Highness.
يمكنكم الآن دخول القصر ومقابلة صاحب السمو.
With a document bearing his signature,
مع وثيقة تحمل توقيعه،
the mortuary will comply at once.
ستمتثل دار الجنازات على الفور.
You...
أنت...
I still have pressing duties to attend to,
لا تزال لدي واجبات ملحة يجب عليّ القيام بها.
so I will not keep you for tea.
لذلك لن أبقيك لتناول الشاي.
Chen Feng.
تشن فنغ.
See our guest out.
نودع ضيفنا.
Yes.
نعم.
Lord Huang,
اللورد هوانغ،
this way, please.
من هنا، من فضلك.
(Ten-Commandment Hall)
(قاعة الوصايا العشر)
(Body Preparation Room)
(غرفة تجهيز الجثث)
From today onward, rotate shifts in three watches.
ابتداءً من اليوم، سيتم تناوب الورديات في ثلاث نوبات.
No one is to enter.
ممنوع دخول أي شخص.
- Yes.
- نعم.
Wu Jiang.
وو جيانغ.
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
His Highness instructed me
أصدر سموه تعليماته لي
to guard the body at all costs.
حماية الجسد بأي ثمن.
No one is to take it away.
لا يحق لأحد أن يأخذه.
I had the same thought as he did.
كانت لدي نفس الفكرة التي راودته.
Understood.
مفهوم.
Carry on with your duties.
استمر في أداء واجباتك.
Master Shenguan
الأستاذ شينغوان
kept his precepts pure throughout his life.
حافظ على مبادئه نقية طوال حياته.
After passing, where would he go?
بعد وفاته، إلى أين سيذهب؟
To the Pure Land.
إلى الأرض الطاهرة.
Not long ago, I heard of a legal case.
سمعتُ قبل فترة وجيزة عن قضية قانونية.
But only part of it.
لكن هذا ليس سوى جزء منه.
I was hoping you
كنت آمل أن
could enlighten me.
قد يفيدني ذلك.
Please go on.
تفضل.
It tells of Master Danxia,
يروي قصة السيد دانكسيا،
who once encountered a beautiful woman
الذي التقى ذات مرة بامرأة جميلة
unable to cross a river.
غير قادر على عبور النهر.
So the master carried her
فحملها السيد
across the river.
عبر النهر.
A fellow practitioner rebuked the master,
وبّخ أحد زملائه في المهنة الأستاذ،
saying this act
قول هذا الفعل
broke the vow of chastity.
خرقت عهد العفة.
Master Danxia replied with just one sentence,
أجاب السيد دانكسيا بجملة واحدة فقط،
and the man attained sudden insight.
وتوصل الرجل فجأة إلى بصيرة.
Master Danxia said,
قال السيد دانكسيا،
"I have already
لقد فعلت ذلك بالفعل
let go of that woman.
دع تلك المرأة ترحل.
Why are you still holding on to her?"
لماذا ما زلت متمسكاً بها؟
It seems that all things in this world
يبدو أن كل شيء في هذا العالم
are shaped by karma,
تتشكل بفعل الكارما،
with no absolute right or wrong.
بدون صواب أو خطأ مطلق.
Everything
كل شئ
begins with intention.
يبدأ بالنية.
As the Sixth Patriarch said,
كما قال البطريرك السادس،
Bodhi has no tree.
لا توجد شجرة في بودي.
The bright mirror has no stand.
المرآة اللامعة ليس لها قاعدة.
Originally there is nothing,
في الأصل لا يوجد شيء،
so where could dust alight?
فأين يمكن أن يستقر الغبار إذن؟
I understand
أفهم
what you mean.
ماذا تقصد.
I also know
أعرف أيضاً
what you seek.
ما تبحث عنه.
Amitabha.
أميتابها.
This is osmanthus wine brewed by Consort Hui herself.
هذا نبيذ الأوسمانثوس الذي قامت بتخميره الكونسورت هوي بنفسها.
Let me
دعني
offers a toast to Your Majesty.
يقدم نخبًا لجلالتكم.
These past days,
في الأيام الماضية،
those old men have been filing complaints about you nonstop.
هؤلاء الرجال المسنون يقدمون شكاوى ضدك بلا توقف.
Look at these memorials.
انظر إلى هذه النصب التذكارية.
I rise early and retire late,
أستيقظ مبكراً وأنام متأخراً،
and half of it is thanks to you.
ونصف ذلك يعود إليك.
I
أنا
acknowledge my fault.
أقر بخطئي.
You are frail,
أنت ضعيف،
and you never drink.
وأنت لا تشرب الكحول أبداً.
Why today?
لماذا اليوم؟
Because I am at fault.
لأنني أنا المخطئ.
Speak.
يتكلم.
Are you prepared?
هل أنت مستعد؟
I ask that Chu Chu
أطلب من تشو تشو
re-examine Master Shenguan.
أعد النظر في وضع المعلم شينغوان.
Xiao Jinyu,
شياو جينيو,
if you pursue this further,
إذا واصلتَ متابعة هذا الأمر،
even I cannot protect you.
حتى أنا لا أستطيع حمايتك.
Do you understand?
هل تفهم؟
I
أنا
understand.
يفهم.
Careful on the turn.
انتبه عند المنعطف.
Do not bump His Highness.
لا تصطدم بصاحب السمو.
Mind His Highness's hand.
انتبهوا ليد صاحب السمو.
Move.
يتحرك.
Steady.
ثابت.
No rush.
لا داعي للعجلة.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Stop.
قف.
One, two, three.
واحد اثنين ثلاثة.
Wu Jiang.
وو جيانغ.
What happened to His Highness?
ماذا حدث لصاحب السمو؟
His Highness...
صاحب السمو...
His Highness drank much with His Majesty.
شرب سموه كثيراً مع جلالة الملك.
Before he passed out,
قبل أن يفقد وعيه،
he repeatedly instructed me
لقد كرر لي التعليمات
to personally deliver
للتسليم شخصيا
His Majesty's written approval to you.
موافقة جلالته الخطية لكم.
I will perform the autopsy on Master Shenguan?
هل سأقوم بتشريح جثة السيد شينغوان؟
His Majesty agreed?
هل وافق جلالته؟
My turn now, right?
دوري الآن، أليس كذلك؟
You said my skull looks good.
قلتَ إن جمجمتي تبدو جيدة.
The best...
الأفضل...
You said it...
لقد قلتها...
You're the best-looking.
أنت الأجمل.
Come on.
تعال.
Get up first.
استيقظ أولاً.
Come.
يأتي.
Turn around. Don't look.
استدر. لا تنظر.
Chu Chu likes corpses the most.
تشو تشو تحب الجثث أكثر من أي شيء آخر.
I am a corpse.
أنا جثة هامدة.
Chu Chu, you like me the most.
تشو تشو، أنتِ تحبينني أكثر من أي شخص آخر.
Yes.
نعم.
I like you the most.
أحبك أكثر من أي شخص آخر.
Look at me.
انظر إليَّ.
The floor is cold.
الأرضية باردة.
Get up first.
استيقظ أولاً.
Wu Jiang.
وو جيانغ.
So it's good news.
إذن، هذا خبر سار.
Come help.
تعالوا للمساعدة.
Come.
يأتي.
One, two, three.
واحد اثنين ثلاثة.
Move.
يتحرك.
Careful.
انتبه.
Here.
هنا.
Support him.
ادعموه.
Slowly.
ببطء.
Here.
هنا.
Careful.
انتبه.
Careful. Don't hit his head.
انتبه. لا تضرب رأسه.
Slowly.
ببطء.
Push him in.
ادفعه للداخل.
Further in.
ثم إلى الداخل.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
He looks slim,
يبدو نحيفاً،
but he's heavy when drunk.
لكنه يصبح ثقيلاً عندما يكون ثملاً.
I'm exhausted.
أنا مرهق.
Wu Jiang.
وو جيانغ.
Go prepare the hangover remedy.
اذهب وحضّر علاجاً للصداع الناتج عن الإفراط في الشرب.
Chen Feng, get water for his feet.
يا تشين فنغ، أحضر الماء لغسل قدميه.
- Yes.
- نعم.
Chu Chu.
تشو تشو.
Then I will be on my way.
ثم سأنطلق في طريقي.
Call for me if anything comes up.
اتصل بي إذا طرأ أي شيء.
Are you feeling uncomfortable anywhere?
هل تشعر بعدم الارتياح في أي مكان؟
It hurts.
إنه مؤلم.
Hurts?
هل يؤلمك؟
Where does it hurt?
حيث أنها لا تؤذي؟
My chest.
صدري.
Chest?
صدر؟
You only had a few cups of wine, right?
لم تشرب سوى بضعة أكواب من النبيذ، أليس كذلك؟
You do not want me anymore.
أنت لا تريدني بعد الآن.
My chest hurts.
صدري يؤلمني.
Your Highness, you are blaming me instead.
يا صاحب السمو، أنت تلقي اللوم عليّ بدلاً من ذلك.
Still sharp even when drunk.
لا يزال حاد الذكاء حتى في حالة السكر.
You stay silent when it is hard to answer.
تلتزم الصمت عندما يصعب عليك الرد.
When have I ever abandoned you?
متى تخليت عنك؟
After drinking so much,
بعد شرب كل هذه الكمية،
it is only natural your chest hurts.
من الطبيعي أن تشعر بألم في صدرك.
Chest hurts...
يؤلمني صدري...
Wine...
خمر...
Autopsy...
تشريح الجثة...
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
The sobering soup is ready.
الحساء المُهدئ جاهز.
You came just in time.
لقد أتيت في الوقت المناسب تماماً.
Do remember to drink it later.
لا تنس أن تشربه لاحقاً.
Be good.
كن طيباً.
Take good care of His Highness.
اعتنوا بصاحب السمو جيداً.
- Yes.
- نعم.
Is Her Highness angry?
هل صاحبة السمو غاضبة؟
How would I know?
كيف لي أن أعرف؟
When His Highness wakes tomorrow,
عندما يستيقظ صاحب السمو غداً،
and remembers tonight,
ويتذكر هذه الليلة،
will he silence us both?
هل سيسكتنا نحن الاثنين؟
Say one more word,
قل كلمة أخرى،
and I will silence you first.
وسأسكتك أولاً.
Go wash His Highness's feet.
اذهب واغسل قدمي صاحب السمو.
How did I get back last night?
كيف عدت الليلة الماضية؟
Wu Jiang and Chen Feng led the way,
قاد وو جيانغ وتشن فنغ الطريق،
I carried you back myself.
حملتك بنفسي إلى الخلف.
Nearly broke my back.
كادت أن تكسر ظهري.
Why are you still here so early?
لماذا ما زلت هنا في هذا الوقت المبكر؟
You really went all in this time.
لقد بذلت كل ما في وسعك هذه المرة.
It is this late and you are still not sober.
لقد تأخر الوقت وما زلت غير واعٍ.
Your father's trick really worked.
لقد نجحت حيلة والدك بالفعل.
Drink yourself senseless first.
اشرب حتى تفقد وعيك أولاً.
That way even His Majesty
وبهذه الطريقة حتى جلالته
cannot press you too hard.
لا يمكنني الضغط عليك بشدة.
Clever.
ماهر.
Just that the aftermath is brutal.
لكن العواقب وخيمة.
What are you laughing at?
ما الذي يضحكك؟
That aftermath
تلك التداعيات
is something only our Chu Chu could handle.
هذا شيء لا يستطيع التعامل معه إلا تشو تشو خاصتنا.
Chu Chu came to take care of me last night?
هل جاءت تشو تشو لتعتني بي الليلة الماضية؟
Be precise.
كن دقيقاً.
It was not her tending to you.
لم تكن هي من تعتني بك.
You were the one clinging to her and refusing to let go.
كنت أنت من تشبث بها ورفضت تركها.
You do not remember it at all?
ألا تتذكر ذلك على الإطلاق؟
Then do you remember
هل تتذكر؟
lying on the floor pretending to be a corpse?
هل يستلقي على الأرض متظاهراً بأنه جثة؟
You told Chu Chu
أخبرتَ تشو تشو
that she likes corpses most and begged her to examine you.
أنها تحب الجثث أكثر من غيرها وتوسلت إليها أن تفحصك.
You are making things up, right?
أنت تختلق الأمور، أليس كذلك؟
I would not dare.
لن أجرؤ على ذلك.
Everyone heard it.
سمعها الجميع.
Where is Chu Chu?
أين تشو تشو؟
The Princess Consort spent the whole night examining bodies.
أمضت الأميرة القرينة الليل كله في فحص الجثث.
She is still in the mortuary.
لا تزال في المشرحة.
Have the kitchen prepare some salted porridge.
اطلب من المطبخ تحضير بعض العصيدة المملحة.
Save it for the Princess Consort.
احتفظي به للأميرة القرينة.
Yes.
نعم.
I stayed out all night.
بقيت بالخارج طوال الليل.
Leng Yue must be worried. I should go.
لا بد أن لينغ يو قلقة. يجب أن أذهب.
Get lost.
اغرب عن وجهي.
Vice Minister, do not go.
نائب الوزير، لا تذهب.
I am never drinking again.
لن أشرب الكحول مرة أخرى.
Good morning, Madam.
صباح الخير سيدتي.
Mengchun,
منغتشون،
why have these plants been moved here?
لماذا تم نقل هذه النباتات إلى هنا؟
They are not usually kept in this courtyard.
لا يتم الاحتفاظ بها عادة في هذه الساحة.
While you and Master Jing were out last night,
بينما كنت أنت والسيد جينغ بالخارج الليلة الماضية،
a petty thief broke into the residence.
اقتحم لص صغير المنزل.
The courtyard was left in a mess.
كانت ساحة الفناء في حالة فوضى عارمة.
The servants are putting things back in order.
يقوم الخدم بإعادة الأمور إلى نصابها.
Did the thief steal anything?
هل سرق اللص شيئاً؟
Please do not worry. Everything has been checked.
لا داعي للقلق. لقد تم فحص كل شيء.
Nothing is missing,
لا يوجد شيء مفقود،
and no one was hurt.
ولم يصب أحد بأذى.
Only a flowerpot by the wall was broken.
لم ينكسر سوى أصيص زهور بجوار الجدار.
Most likely crushed when the thief landed there.
على الأرجح سُحقت عندما هبط اللص هناك.
Take me to see
خذني لأرى
where the thief came in.
حيث دخل اللص.
Yes.
نعم.
This way, please.
من هنا، من فضلك.
It looks like
يبدو أن
the footprint is about the same size as my lord's.
حجم البصمة مماثل تقريبًا لحجم بصمة سيدي.
The flowerpot...
أصيص الزهور...
Lady Jing,
السيدة جينغ،
this is just an ordinary plant.
هذا مجرد نبات عادي.
There is nothing unusual about it.
لا يوجد شيء غير عادي في ذلك.
Then you may keep it.
عندها يمكنك الاحتفاظ به.
Madam.
سيدتي.
I was going to report to Your Highness
كنت سأقدم تقريراً إلى سموكم
that the autopsy is complete,
أن عملية التشريح قد اكتملت،
and that we can investigate the Zhao Residence again.
وأننا نستطيع التحقيق في مقر إقامة تشاو مرة أخرى.
Since Your Highness is still asleep,
بما أن صاحب السمو لا يزال نائماً،
I will go on my own.
سأذهب بمفردي.
Already awake?
مستيقظ بالفعل؟
I am.
أنا أكون.
The one down there,
الذي في الأسفل،
you were drunk yesterday,
كنتَ ثملاً بالأمس،
spouting nonsense.
كلام فارغ.
Now that you are sober,
الآن وقد أصبحتَ رصيناً،
you have nothing to say?
ليس لديك ما تقوله؟
I was wrong.
كنت مخطئاً.
In the statements you read every day,
في البيانات التي تقرأها كل يوم،
people rarely say much?
نادراً ما يتحدث الناس كثيراً؟
Last night was my fault.
الليلة الماضية كانت خطئي.
You spoke vaguely,
لقد تحدثت بشكل مبهم،
which shows
وهذا يُظهر
a lack of sincerity.
انعدام الإخلاص.
I lost my composure when drunk,
أفقد رباطة جأشي عندما أكون ثملاً،
and caused you trouble.
وتسببت لك في مشاكل.
I am sorry.
أنا آسف.
I...
أنا...
I should not have decided on my own
ما كان ينبغي لي أن أقرر بمفردي
to keep you away from this case.
لإبعادك عن هذه القضية.
What I resented was myself.
ما كنت أكرهه هو نفسي.
Since our marriage,
منذ زواجنا،
I have failed to shield you from hardship.
لقد فشلت في حمايتك من المشقة.
Instead, I brought storms to your side.
بل جلبت العواصف إلى جانبك.
I feared that, in time,
كنت أخشى أنه مع مرور الوقت،
you might regret choosing me.
قد تندم على اختيارك لي.
Chu Chu.
تشو تشو.
I am sorry.
أنا آسف.
Why must it be you alone who shields me?
لماذا يجب أن تكون أنت وحدك من يحميني؟
If these storms
إذا كانت هذه العواصف
are already part of who you are,
هي بالفعل جزء من هويتك،
then it means
إذن هذا يعني
you were standing in the wind and rain
كنت تقف في مهب الريح والمطر
long before they ever reached me.
قبل وقت طويل من وصولهم إليّ.
People say husband and wife are paired wings,
يقول الناس إن الزوج والزوجة جناحان متلازمان.
branches grown together.
نمت الأغصان معاً.
How could one stand in the storm
كيف يمكن للمرء أن يقف في وجه العاصفة؟
while the other stays outside it?
بينما يبقى الآخر خارجه؟
Unless
إلا إذا
you never meant to be my partner at all.
لم تكن تنوي أبدًا أن تكون شريكي.
Of course I did.
بالطبع فعلت.
But all I have brought you
لكن كل ما أحضرته لكم
are rumors and trouble.
إنها شائعات ومشاكل.
You treat me so well
أنت تعاملني بشكل جيد للغاية
that I no longer know what to do.
لم أعد أعرف ماذا أفعل.
You are always like this.
أنت دائماً على هذا الحال.
You forget your own kindness
تنسى لطفك بنفسك
the moment you give it.
لحظة أن تعطيه إياه.
Yet every kindness shown to you,
ومع ذلك، كل إحسان يُظهر لك،
you carry it carefully in your heart.
تحملها بعناية في قلبك.
But that is all right.
لكن لا بأس بذلك.
I have kept
لقد احتفظت
your kindness clearly in my heart.
لطفك واضح في قلبي.
No one can twist right and wrong.
لا يمكن لأحد أن يحرف الصواب والخطأ.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
The dignified Commandery Prince An
أمير القيادة المحترم
left without a word to live separately.
تُركوا دون كلمة واحدة ليعيشوا منفصلين.
Tell me,
أخبرني،
what crime is that?
ما هذه الجريمة؟
I admit my fault.
أعترف بخطئي.
It will never happen again.
لن يتكرر ذلك أبداً.
Are you sober now?
هل أنت رصين الآن؟
My mind is clear.
ذهني صافٍ.
As if reborn.
كأنها ولدت من جديد.
Then there is something important I must tell you.
ثم هناك شيء مهم يجب أن أخبرك به.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
The cause of Master Shenguan's death
سبب وفاة المعلم شينغوان
is indeed suspicious.
إنه أمر مثير للريبة بالفعل.
♪Time drips away like fading crimson scent♪
♪ يمر الوقت ببطء كرائحة قرمزية تتلاشى ♪
♪The hardships of arrival pass in a fleeting blink♪
♪تمر صعوبات الوصول في غمضة عين♪
♪Palm lines carry the footprints of memory♪
خطوط الكف تحمل آثار الذكريات
♪Leading us out of every winding turn♪
♪يقودنا للخروج من كل منعطف متعرج♪
♪If two hearts can fly as one then storms are part of the way♪
♪إذا استطاع قلبان أن يطيرا كقلب واحد، فإن العواصف جزء من الطريق♪
♪Looking back the sky has already cleared♪
♪بالنظر إلى الوراء، تكون السماء قد صفت بالفعل♪
♪Your branches entwined with mine♪
♪أغصانك متشابكة مع أغصاني♪
♪Bound together in mutual reliance♪
♪مترابطون في الاعتماد المتبادل♪
♪Rugged roads become the paths of sun and moon♪
♪تتحول الطرق الوعرة إلى مسارات للشمس والقمر♪
♪Fireflies like stars circle through the seasons♪
♪تحلق اليراعات كالنجوم عبر الفصول♪
♪Shining with the hope of dreams♪
♪متألقة بأمل الأحلام♪
♪This world is no longer in rags♪
♪لم يعد هذا العالم في حالة يرثى لها♪
♪Only by holding you in my heart do I dare embrace fear♪
♪فقط من خلال الاحتفاظ بك في قلبي أجرؤ على مواجهة الخوف♪
♪Quietly waiting for rumors to fade♪
♪أنتظر بهدوء أن تتلاشى الشائعات♪
♪Together we face the tides of fate♪
معًا نواجه تقلبات القدر
♪Turning the course of heaven and earth♪
♪تغيير مسار السماء والأرض♪
♪This love was never easy♪
♪لم يكن هذا الحب سهلاً أبداً♪
♪So life and death will not part us♪
♪لذا لن يفرقنا الموت والحياة♪
♪Like sinking into the deep sea♪
♪كأنك تغرق في أعماق البحر♪
♪The first breath upon awakening♪
♪أول نفس عند الاستيقاظ♪
♪This bond will never waver♪
♪لن تتزعزع هذه الرابطة أبدًا♪
♪So we stay together till our hair turns white♪
♪سنبقى معاً حتى يشيب شعرنا♪
♪I ask time itself to hold the pen♪
♪أطلب من الزمن نفسه أن يمسك القلم♪
♪And write the ending of eternity♪
♪واكتب نهاية الأبدية♪
♪This love was never easy♪
♪لم يكن هذا الحب سهلاً أبداً♪
♪So I believe without doubt♪
♪لذا فأنا أؤمن بلا شك♪
♪Like a thousand sails passing by♪
♪كألف شراع يمرّ♪
♪Reaching shore at the first light of dawn♪
♪الوصول إلى الشاطئ مع أول ضوء للفجر♪
♪This bond will never waver♪
♪لن تتزعزع هذه الرابطة أبدًا♪
♪So joy and sorrow are no longer ours to choose♪
♪لذا لم يعد لنا أن نختار بين الفرح والحزن ♪
♪I will prove it with the rest of my life♪
سأثبت ذلك طوال حياتي.
♪Together at the edge of the world without an end♪
♪معًا على حافة العالم الذي لا نهاية له♪